DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
Hey, are you sure we're on the right path?
我問你們，是不是走錯路了啊？
Yup, these are the stairs we need to take.
不，就是走這階梯沒錯
After these steps, we'll reach the fifth basement floor,
走下去就能到地下五層
close to the orc settlement.
是半獸人聚落的附近
At least that's what it says on the map.
地圖上是這麼寫的
How are we supposed to go down these steps?
這是要怎麼走下去啊？
This is incredible.
真是驚人
There's a wide variety of Tentacles growing here.
到處長滿了各種觸手呢
The orcs totally made a fool of us.
看來我們被半獸人欺騙了
They kindly laid a trap for us.
真是精心設想的惡作劇
I'm not so sure.
那可不一定
This route leads to their settlement.
我相信這是通往聚落的道路
It's ideal for keeping away outsiders at least.
這樣的環境正好能防止外人靠近
Let's try moving forward.
我們試著前進吧
Given the time and effort that would take, taking a detour might be a quicker option.
考量到要花費的力氣跟時間 繞遠路可能還比較快
Marcille, don't get too close to the walls.
瑪露希爾，不要太靠近牆壁
These creatures lurk within the walls.
這些傢伙就潛伏在牆壁裡
Places teeming with Tentacles have just as many cavities.
有很多觸手的地方 就代表此處有相當多的空洞
It also means there are many traps and devices.
也就是說陷阱跟機關也不少
The Tentacles crush and break these devices
觸手會壓壞機關
and they even grow on treasure chests, working mischief together with the traps.
還會長在寶箱上跟陷阱一起使壞
They're monsters I want to see exterminated next to Mimics!
是繼寶箱怪之後 我最希望毀滅的魔物！
There.
好
I think we made some pretty good progress…
我們應該前進不少了吧…
Strange.
真奇怪
The orcs must've used this path to climb to the third floor.
那些半獸人應該也是 通過這裡到第三層
How did they manage to navigate this area?
到底是怎麼走過這種地方的？
Something's here.
有東西在這裡
Be careful.
大家小心
Kensuke!
劍助！
It's a Giant Frog!
是大青蛙！
Ugh, so gross!
天哪，好噁心！
No way!
不會吧！
I got this! Aslam!
交給我對付！阿斯拉姆！
No!
不要啊！
Ambrosia!
安布洛西雅！
Senshi, behind you!
先西，注意身後！
Don't let go!
不能放手！
Hang in there, Senshi!
撐住啊，先西！
M-Magic…
魔法…
-It should be close enough. -No! It's too close!
-如果是這距離就能打中 -住手！太近了！
This is bad.
這下糟了
What do we do?
該怎麼辦？
Is that a trap?
那是陷阱？
There's a Tentacles growing unnaturally from the wall next to the frog.
在青蛙的旁邊 不自然地生長出來的觸手
It's probably growing out of the exit of a trap.
它大概就扎根在陷阱的噴射口上
If I can extract it, I could trigger the trap.
如果能除掉它，就可以啟動陷阱
But…
但是…
how do I pull it out?
該怎麼把它拔出來？
If I touch it directly, my hands will get swollen.
如果直接觸碰，我的手就會腫起來
Laios!
萊歐斯！
Why are Giant Frogs safe even when in contact with the Tentacles?
為什麼大青蛙即使碰到觸手也沒事？
Huh?
什麼？
No idea.
我也不知道耶
Maybe it's their biological makeup.
可能是因為魔物的體質吧
So, you don't have any info on this?
原來他不曉得相關知識？
Children can be inquisitive regardless of the situation, huh?
小孩的好奇心 在任何場合都可能被激發呢
Fine!
算了！
Chilchuck!
奇爾查克！
It doesn't hurt!
不會痛！
I can do this!
這下行得通！
Huh?
奇怪？
I can't pull it out!
我拔不起來！
-Chilchuck!
-奇爾查克！
Chilchuck!
奇爾查克！
He's alive.
他還活著
Show me your hands!
讓我看看你的手！
Huh? They're unhurt.
奇怪？沒有受傷
I see.
原來如此
He wrapped his hands with the skin of a Giant Frog.
他是用大青蛙的皮包住自己的手
Well done!
你還真拚啊！
Chilchuck,
奇爾查克
this is a really great idea!
這真是個好主意！
Dissect a Giant Frog
剖開大青蛙
and remove the skin from its body.
將皮剝離身體
U-Um, hey…
呃，那個…
Peel the Tentacles
觸手的部分則剝皮
and save the narrow sections for later.
把纖細的尖端都先取出
Boil the thicker portions,
然後水煮粗的部分
then, after boiling, mash them and knead with flour.
都煮好後，將其弄碎，並與麵粉混合
Shape the mixture into sticks, and slice them into bite-sized pieces,
將麵團捏成棒狀後，切成適當的大小
and boil once more.
再放回去水煮
Hey…
我說啊…
Lightly dry the Giant Frog skins,
稍微風乾大青蛙的皮後
take various measurements, and sew.
測量各部位的尺寸後進行縫製
Heat olive oil, garlic, and hot pepper in a pan,
倒入橄欖油、大蒜、鷹爪椒
then add the thigh meat of a Giant Frog and sauté them together.
再加入大青蛙的大腿肉翻炒
-It's done!
-就完成了！
TENTACLES GNOCCHI, TENTACLES PASTA, FROG SUIT
（觸手麵疙瘩 觸手義大利麵，青蛙套裝）
Ugh, just great!
天哪，真是夠了！
Bring them to me one person at a time!
你們輪流拿過來！
You guys finished your tasks while I was debating which of you to stop!
在我還沒想好要先阻止誰前 你們就做好了！
Come on, now, just give it a try.
別計較，你就穿穿看嘛
Yes, give it a bite at least.
是啊，至少嘗一口看看嘛
I said one person at a time!
我不是叫你們輪流來嗎？
And who knows whether they're really safe or not?
也不知道到底安不安全
WHISPER
（竊竊私語）
I think you'll look really cute in it, Marcille.
瑪露希爾，你穿上這件一定很可愛
You look so cute!
好可愛…
The color really suits you.
顏色很亮眼，很適合你
I like how your ears are contributing to that frog-like silhouette.
耳朵部分的輪廓很像青蛙 挺好看的喔
Let's get moving.
我們趕快走吧
Right.
好
Wow! It doesn't hurt at all!
好厲害！完全不會痛！
Ugh, this is so disgusting!
我的天哪，好噁心…
How beautiful.
真是漂亮啊
It's delicious.
好好吃喔
Kensuke!
劍助！
Thank goodness!
太好了！
Look!
你們看！
It's the castle town.
是城邊小鎮
We're already on the fifth floor!
這裡已經是第五層了！
There are signs of people fleeing in panic.
有慌忙逃跑的痕跡
It seems the orcs were speaking the truth.
看來半獸人說的果然是真的
It's certain that there's a Red Dragon around here.
炎龍確實就在這附近
Let's stay vigilant and ready for combat as we move ahead.
我們要小心前進，準備隨時戰鬥
Huh?
奇怪？
It seems like the Giant Frog's blood
好像是大青蛙的血
has congealed inside and got stuck to my clothes.
從內側凝固，黏在我的衣服上面
We didn't have enough time to dry the skins, after all.
畢竟我們當時沒有 足夠的時間充分鞣製蛙皮
Are we going to fight the dragon like this?
難道我們要穿成這樣跟龍戰鬥嗎？
How am I supposed to reunite with Falin now, huh?!
這樣我怎麼有臉 跟法琳重逢啊？我問你！
Answer me!
回答我！
-It feels like my insides are spinning. -Kiki, Kaka.
-感覺我的體內在翻攪 -奇奇、卡卡
Show Namari to the guest room so she can rest.
你們帶娜瑪莉去客房休息
I will go to report to the Lord of the Island.
我去跟島主報告
So, how was it inside the dungeon?
所以迷宮的狀況如何？
The most concerning thing
說到特別讓我在意的地方
is that it has become a rough place.
就是治安變得不好
All the treasures down to the third basement floor
到地下三層的寶物
have been plundered.
全都被掠奪一空
And there are now more hangouts for outlaws.
不法之徒廝混的地方變多了
What's worse,
更糟糕的是
orc hordes have started appearing on the upper floors and causing trouble.
半獸人集團開始出現在淺層 時常惹麻煩的樣子
You should consider deploying a troop or offering rewards to deal with them.
我認為可以派遣軍隊 或提供懸賞金緝拿他們
I wonder where the orcs entered from.
他們到底是從哪裡闖進來的？
I suspect that some old dwarf mines might be connected to the dungeon.
或許跟矮人族的古老坑道相通吧
Orcs tend to inhabit such passages.
半獸人都定居在那種洞穴中
Dwarves, huh?
矮人族啊？
How abominable.
實在是太可恨了
They're like moles.
他們簡直就像鼴鼠
No matter how you seal off their passages, they keep making more.
不管你再補多少洞 他們還是在各處挖出更多洞
A long time ago,
在很久以前
the elves and dwarves divided into the east and west in conflict.
精靈族與矮人族 各分東西彼此爭鬥的時代
They say the dwarves hid in these lands and waited for the arrival of the elves.
據說當時矮人族就藏身於此地 等待精靈族的到來
Even after the war, they continued to dig tunnels,
即使戰爭結束了，他們仍持續挖洞
eventually swallowing the Golden City and turning it into a dungeon.
最終吞併黃金都城，造就迷宮
I hear that the surviving dwarves are responsible
聽說迷宮之所以仍持續擴張
for the dungeon's ongoing expansion.
都是因為存活下來的矮人後裔害的
That rumor cannot be trusted.
那種傳言不足以為信
Anyhow, here is the magic circle I copied.
這是我本次臨摹的魔法陣
It's in Elvish, like all the others.
與至今的相同，是用精靈語撰寫
And based on the handwriting, the author is likely the same individual.
從筆跡來看應該是同一個人寫的
There are absolutely no traces of anyone tampering with it.
完全沒有其他人竄改的痕跡
The lord of the dungeon,
這一定是迷宮之主
the lunatic magician, is most certainly the one who made this.
也就是狂亂魔術師所寫下的
Is he an elf?
那傢伙是精靈嗎？
I can't be certain,
我無法斷定
but this magic is beyond the capabilities of a tall-man or a dwarf.
但這是長身人與矮人無法駕馭的法術
What a tricky situation.
真是頭疼啊
The thing is, I received a letter from the western elves the other day.
其實前幾天西方的精靈寄來一封信
It said, "The dungeon is our heritage. Return it to us."
信中寫著“迷宮是我們的遺產 快還給我們”
What a selfish demand!
未免也太自私了！
They're the ones who took this land from the dwarves
當初因為他們 從矮人那邊奪來的土地有剩
and handed it over to humans because they didn't know what to do with it!
才讓給人類的不是嗎？
Ignore them.
不用理他們
This land was granted by the king of the elves himself.
這塊土地姑且是精靈王賜予的
I can't just do that.
我不能那樣做
They'll take this island, too.
那整座島都會被他們奪走
That won't do.
那樣可就傷腦筋了
There must be great treasure still hidden in that dungeon.
應該還有無數的財寶沉眠於迷宮啊
Lord of the Island,
島主大人
the elves aren't after the treasure.
那些精靈的目的並非是財寶
They're after the spell of immortality that is cast on the dungeon.
而是施加在迷宮中的不死之術
The magic that ties the soul to the body is still a big mystery.
將靈魂固定在肉體上的魔法 至今仍充滿謎團
When that mystery is solved, its worth will far surpass that of gold.
只要解開此謎團 其價值連黃金也比不上
We must figure it out before the elves do.
我們該搶先精靈一步，去揭開真相
Are you suggesting we copy every single magic circle to study them?
你是要我們 臨摹並研究所有的魔法陣嗎？
Listen carefully!
請你聽好！
When such great magic is involved, there is always a blueprint.
如此龐大的魔法一定會有藍圖存在
Get your hands on it!
要想方設法去取得！
As long as you have it,
只要拿到那東西
you can give up the dungeon or anything you please.
管他是迷宮還是什麼都可以獻上
Once the elves know you possess it,
只要精靈發現我們手中有設計書
they will finally treat you as an equal,
他們才會願意平等地對待你
no, they will kneel before you to negotiate with you.
不，他們甚至會跪著跟你談判
I-Is that so?
這是真的嗎？
So? Where can I find this blueprint?
那麼設計書在哪裡呢？
That's simple.
想也知道
It's likely in the possession of the lord of the dungeon.
設計書就在迷宮之主手上
In other words, you want me to keep backing the explorers?
也就是說，你希望我 老老實實地支援探索者？
Precisely.
正是如此
Don't bargain down the prices for hunting monsters
千萬不要拉低討伐魔物的獎金
and the loot from the dungeons.
或低價購買從迷宮掠奪的物品
Don't hoard your wealth and provide even more support.
避免囤積財富 提供比以往更多的補助
Very well.
我知道了
I'll offer rewards for taking down orcs.
我就提供懸賞金緝拿半獸人吧
What do I say to the elves?
那該怎麼回覆精靈比較好？
I'll help you buy time.
我來幫你爭取時間
Laios, was it?
我記得他是叫萊歐斯吧？
He was a skilled adventurer,
他是實力高超的冒險者
but I wonder how far his party can advance.
不曉得他們一行人能前進到哪裡
Good morning, Namari.
早安，娜瑪莉
How are you feeling?
身體還好嗎？
My axe!
我的斧頭呢？
Your stuff is right here.
你的東西在那裡
And
還有啊
here's money from Grandpa Tansu.
這是坦斯爺爺給你的錢
It's more than I expected.
比我想的還多耶
There might be a little break,
接下來雖然會有一段空檔
but he said he wanted to request your help again.
但他說想要再請你幫忙
T-Thanks.
謝啦
I owe you.
承蒙你們照顧了
I'll walk you to the street.
我送你到街上吧
Do you have a home?
你有家嗎？
Or do you stay at an inn?
還是在外住宿？
Neither. I'm heading toward the dungeon.
我沒有要回去，是要去迷宮那邊
Why?
為什麼？
You're going under again?
你還要再進去嗎？
No.
不是…
I have an errand to the nearby temple.
我要去附近的寺院處理一些事
An errand?
處理一些事？
It's the resurrection office.
這是復活處
Namari!
是娜瑪莉啊！
Is it true you left Laios' party?
聽說你離開萊歐斯的隊伍了 這是真的嗎？
So, what are you looking for? An item or a person?
所以你是來找遺失物？還是找人？
A person.
找人
A female tall-man with light brown hair.
長身人女孩，淡褐色頭髮
It's around shoulder length.
頭髮長度到肩膀上方
She's somewhere between…
年齡的話…
her teens and her forties.
大概是10幾歲到40幾歲
Wait. Do you mean Laios' sister?
等一下，你是在說萊歐斯的妹妹嗎？
She's in her twenties at most.
她大概20歲上下吧
You should get your eyes checked.
你該去看眼科了
It's hard to guess the age of people from other races, okay?
我怎麼可能知道其他種族的年齡啊
We have no corpse here that fits that description.
沒有收到符合那條件的屍體
I see.
是這樣啊
On the fifth basement floor,
地下五層
outside the Golden Castle, lies the castle town.
穿過黃金城堡後，有一座城邊小鎮
The streets, expanded and warped by magic,
因為魔法而擴張扭曲的街道
show traces of a time when they bustled with activity.
所到之處皆留有昔日繁榮時代的痕跡
Figures pass by the edge of your vision.
眼角餘光彷彿能瞥見有誰經過
You hear whispers.
彷彿能聽到有誰在呢喃
Such peculiar sensations wash over you.
會讓人有如此奇妙的錯覺
Seems like this was the location for the orc settlement.
這裡就是曾經是半獸人聚落的地方
They must have left in quite a rush.
他們似乎走得很匆忙
The pantry doors are left wide open.
連食品儲藏室也都開著
What an awful stench.
好難聞的味道
Looks like the monsters in this area scavenged this place.
看來有被這附近的魔物搜刮過
It seems the flour and alcohol are safe, though.
不過麵粉和酒似乎沒被波及
Let's make bread.
我們來做麵包吧
The orcs won't be happy when they come back.
半獸人回來後會生氣的
We gave them vegetables, so it's a fair exchange.
我們有給他們蔬菜 這是公平的以物易物
Wargs.
是魔狼
It wasn't a fire, was it?
並不是因為火災，對吧？
No.
不是
They were defeated by the Red Dragon's fire breath.
牠們是被炎龍的火之吐息燒死的
The dragon passed through here not too long ago.
表示炎龍最近經過了這裡
H-Hey.
我問你
You mentioned before
你之前有說過吧？
that dragons sleep most of the time and rarely move about.
龍偶爾才出來活動 大部分的時間都在睡覺
But based on what the orcs told us and the current situation,
但依半獸人的證詞 再加上眼前的情況
it's still on the move.
可見從那之後炎龍都在移動
It's likely roaming around this area even now.
現在大概也在這附近遊蕩
We might've had a chance against a sleeping dragon.
我們或許可以贏過沉睡中的龍
But do you really think we could defeat it with our current strength?
可是憑現在的我們 真的可以打過對方嗎？
What if we lose again?
如果我們又輸了怎麼辦？
What if she's already digested?
要是她早就已經被消化掉 該如何是好？
Calm down.
冷靜點
We don't know that yet.
我們還無法確定
Let's figure out a plan first.
總之先擬定計畫吧
But taking on the dragon
就算你那麼說
with just the three of you is gonna be tough.
你們得靠三人的力量戰鬥啊
The three of us?
三人？
I keep telling you this, but don't count on me to help in combat!
我說過好幾次了 不要期待我成為戰力！
My only job is to get you to your destination!
我的工作只是 協助你們來到這裡而已！
We know that.
我們明白
We're not blaming you.
又沒有在怪你
M-My mistake then.
是我錯了
How have you defeated dragons in the past?
你們之前是怎麼打敗龍的？
It depends on the time, circumstances, and the type of dragon.
要看時機、場合還有龍的種類而定
But usually, Falin casts a spell to protect against fire and harm.
法琳會先詠唱防火焰及受傷的魔法
Then, Namari, Shuro, and I work to slow it down.
接著我跟娜瑪莉、修洛會拖住龍
Marcille weakens the dragon with explosive spells.
由瑪露希爾使出爆炸魔法 削弱牠的力量
Finally, Shuro strikes the killing blow when the opportunity arises.
最後由修洛看準時機使出致命一擊
I think that's how it usually goes.
大多都是這種流程
Of course, it was only possible because of that team.
當然這也要有那些成員才可以做到
Now, we have to figure out a plan for just the three of us.
必須要想出我們三人可以做到的方式
Dragons are resistant to spells and weapons.
魔法和武器對龍都沒有什麼效果
It's because they're covered in steel-like scales.
因為龍身上布滿如鋼鐵般的鱗片
Their only weak spot where you can land a killing blow
但在牠的脖子下方
is the underside of their neck.
有唯一能帶給牠致命傷的逆鱗
Stab it there, and we win!
只要刺中那裡就能贏
The underside of their neck, huh?
脖子下方？
How large is this Red Dragon?
那個炎龍有多大隻？
Let's see…
我想想…
Look over there.
你看那邊
See that half-collapsed walkway?
看到那處崩塌的走道了嗎？
It's about that tall.
大概那麼高
I mean,
不如說
isn't it broken because the dragon bumped its head on it?
那就是龍撞到頭的痕跡吧？
You're right.
你說得對
It's massive.
真大隻啊
Striking it at that height is almost impossible.
要砍到那麼高的地方可是非常困難的
That's exactly the problem.
就是說啊
Let's make our way to the walkway.
我們靠近現場看看吧
It's so high.
好高啊
What if we try jumping onto the dragon's neck from here?
如果從這裡跳到龍的脖子上呢？
-No way! -Forget it.
-不可能… -放棄吧
I can cast defense spells,
我可以詠唱防禦魔法
but I'm not as skilled as Falin.
但我的技術沒有法琳那麼高超
I can't protect you from a fall from this height
我無法讓從這高度跳下的你毫髮無傷
or from fire breath.
也無法防止你被火之吐息傷害
Yeah, what about its fire breath?
對啊，要如何防範火之吐息？
Up here, there's nowhere for us to run.
在這種地方無處可逃啊
And according to Namari,
而且根據娜瑪莉所說
Senshi's axe won't even make a dent in the dragon.
連先西的斧頭也無法起作用
Are you sure your sword can hurt it, Laios?
你確定自己的劍傷得了牠嗎？萊歐斯
To cast an explosive spell strong enough to stun a dragon,
如果要讓我詠唱出 足以讓龍昏迷的爆炸魔法
I'll need you to buy me a lot of time.
需要壓制牠來爭取時間
On top of that, someone needs to land the killing blow.
另外要有人給出致命一擊才能殺掉牠
Can you and Senshi handle all that?
靠你跟先西可以做到那些事嗎？
We'll find a way somehow.
我們會想辦法的
How?
要怎麼做？
Rather than aiming for its head,
我們不瞄準炎龍的頭
what if we blow up a building?
把建築物炸掉如何？
There are a lot of bridges and walkways between buildings here.
這裡有很多 橫跨在建築物間的橋跟房子
We could set off an explosion just as the dragon passes underneath.
我們在龍穿過下方時引爆
The debris will trap the dragon,
用瓦礫封住牠的話
bringing its weak spot within reach.
逆鱗就會在觸手可及的位置
Then, we could strike without worrying about a counterattack.
能藉此防止牠反擊，安心進攻
It's true that the two of us can't buy you enough time to set up your spell.
只靠我們倆的話 確實無法幫你爭取準備時間
But we could make a run for it and lead the dragon on a chase.
但我們可以在逃離龍之餘誘導牠
The streets here are too narrow for the Red Dragon,
對炎龍來說這座城邊小鎮的路很窄
and it's probably feeling worn out after all its activity.
長時間的活動應該讓牠感到相當疲累
If we lead it along the right path, we could tire it out even more.
巧妙安排要走的路 就能讓牠耗費更多的體力
I see.
原來如此
I could help with that.
那樣的話我也可以幫忙
Really?
真的嗎？
Thank you! You're the best!
謝謝你！好開心喔！
Still, why isn't it sleeping?
雖說如此，為什麼牠沒有在睡覺？
Its appearance on the fifth floor is a mystery, too.
出現在第五層的原因也是一個謎
It's persistently prowling these narrow streets that it dislikes.
竟執拗地在牠本該討厭的窄路間徘徊
Could it be its mating season?
難不成是處於發情期？
No…
可是…
Hey, didn't Namari mention something
話說回來，娜瑪莉不是說過
about Senshi's pot being made of seriously tough metal?
先西的鍋子是用 很厲害的金屬製作的嗎？
What was it again?
是叫做什麼來著？
"It shields against a dragon's something and can shatter a dragon's something."
“防禦龍的什麼，打碎龍的什麼”
You're right!
她有說過！
She said every blacksmith dreams of it!
還說是所有鐵匠都夢寐以求的東西
If it shields against a dragon's something,
如果說它能防禦龍的什麼
it's gotta be fire breath!
絕對就是火之吐息吧！
Well, that solves the fire breath problem.
這下如何抵擋 火之吐息的問題也解決了
Isn't your cooking knife made from special metal, too?
該不會連你的菜刀也是特製的吧？
We should've had Namari take a look at it.
我們應該要讓娜瑪莉看一下才對
I'm feeling pretty hopeful now.
總覺得能順利成功
When you put your mind to it, a way opens, huh?
只要去思考，就能找出一條生路呢
All right!
好！
Let's do our research to map out our luring route!
我們事先調查逃跑路線吧！
So, you're back.
你們回來啦
Senshi, you slipped away without a heads-up!
先西，你竟突然跑不見！
I was making bread.
老夫在做麵包
Did you have to do it right before we're facing a dragon?
我們可是正要去打倒龍耶
Absolutely.
老夫當然知道
We have a big mission ahead,
接下來有很重大的工作要做
and the most important thing is to fill our stomachs.
那填飽肚子比任何事都來得重要
We lost to the Red Dragon because of hunger once.
我們曾經因為餓肚子而輸給炎龍
We shouldn't make the same mistake, right?
不能重蹈覆轍，對吧？
Wine!
是葡萄酒！
I humbly took some from the pantry.
老夫是從食品儲藏室拿來的
Save it for after we defeat the dragon.
等我們打贏龍再喝吧
We're missing eggs,
雖然沒有蛋
but these should be enough to make that dish.
但有了這些就能做出那道料理
Grate the bread into crumbs,
用刨絲器將麵包磨成粉末
and marinate the Giant Frog meat with salt and pepper.
用胡椒鹽將大青蛙的肉調味
Dip it in a water and flour batter,
泡進與水混合的麵粉
and coat it with bread crumbs.
再撒上麵包粉
Heat up some olive oil, and deep fry.
加熱橄欖油後油炸
Boil down red wine with seasoning to make a sauce.
熬煮紅酒與調味料來製作醬汁
It's done!
完成了！
CUTLETS TO CONQUER THE RED DRAGON
（戰勝炎龍炸肉排）
That looks amazing!
看起來好美味！
The smell is making me hungry.
一聞到味道就餓了
-Let's dig in!
-開動了！
It's so crispy!
好酥脆喔！
Are you okay, Marcille?
怎麼了？瑪露希爾
The thought of not having to eat monsters soon
一想到就快要不用吃魔物餐了
is making me emotional.
就覺得十分感慨
There's still the Red Dragon, though.
還剩炎龍喔
Listen,
該怎麼說好呢？
there's something I want to say to you all.
我想跟大家說一件事
I doubt I could've made it all this way on my own.
光靠我一個人是無法走到這裡的
Senshi, thank you so much.
先西，真的很感謝你
You were kind to complete strangers like us.
你對素不相識的我們如此親切
Your excellent cooking not only satisfied our hunger
你做的美食不只滿足我們的胃
but it lifted our spirits as well.
也撫慰了我們的心靈
Chilchuck, without you, we would've had to take multiple detours,
奇爾查克，要是沒有你 我們就會繞好幾次遠路
which would have caused days of delay.
晚好幾天到達這裡
Above all, you were dependable.
更重要的是，你非常可靠
And Marcille,
還有瑪露希爾
I'm sorry for the tough time you had on this unfamiliar journey.
抱歉讓你在不習慣的旅途中吃苦
When you said you'd join me, I was so moved.
當你說願意跟我來時，我非常開心
Everyone, thank you so much.
大家，真的很謝謝你們
-S-Sure.
-不用客氣啦
Poor timing!
時機不對！
Sorry.
抱歉
What's this?
怎麼回事？
Seeing it again, it really is huge.
再看一次才發現有夠大
Could we really defeat it?
我們真的贏得過那種魔物嗎？
Don't worry.
沒問題的
The four of us have made it this far.
光我們四人就走到這裡了
As per the plan, Marcille will take her position,
那麼就如同作戰計畫 瑪露希爾到說好的位置
and we'll lure the dragon!
而我們則去誘導龍！
Is everyone ready?
大家準備好了嗎？
Is everyone in good shape?
身體狀態都良好吧？
All right.
好
Let's go!
我們上吧！
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：王姮婕